Who's after
是谁在找
the girl in the photo?
照片上这个女孩儿
Officer, you must be joking.
警官您真会说笑
This is a pawnshop.
我们这是当铺
I don't quite understand
小的听不明白
what you're getting at.
您在说什么
You do.
你明白
Just a moment.
那你等会儿
Going to call someone?
叫人去啊
Just need to pee.
尿急 尿急
Hold it.
憋着
Yes.
是
Just two of them.
就两个人
One looks like a rustic,
一个人土里土气的
the other's in a police uniform.
另外一个穿了警服
Not sure what his deal is.
不知道什么来头呀
Yes, they're here right now.
对 人现在就在这里
Haven't seen you two before.
以前没见过二位
First time here?
头一回来呀
Right.
对
Then I'll assume
那我就当你们是
you don't understand the rules.
不懂这儿的规矩了
I'm paid
我收钱
to find this girl.
替人找这个女孩儿
I can't take any money
就不能再收钱
to give away my client.
把找女孩儿的人给卖了
No double deals from me.
同一件事不做两回买卖
Even if your friend here
就算你身边这位
comes in uniform,
穿着制服也不行
it makes no difference.
这是规矩
Quite a stickler for rules, aren't you?
你还挺讲规矩
But without answers,
但今天我们拿不到答案
we're not leaving today.
我们是不会走的
I know a few friends
我在公安局呢
in the Public Security Bureau, too.
也是认识几位朋友的
May I ask, officer,
敢问这位警官
what's your background?
什么来头啊
It would be a shame if we upset
咱们别大水冲了龙王庙
each other unnecessarily.
就不好了
From the Police Dept?
总局的
A police station?
分局
Surely not just a station house?
不会是警察所的吧
Take them out! Both of them!
轰出去 轰出去 轰出去
Get out!
出去
You two rookies from some station house
两个警察所的毛头小子
burst into my shop in broad daylight,
大白天闯进来砸我的店
breaking my rules.
坏我的规矩
Did you ever think you might not walk out?
就没想过有来无回吗
Deputy Hong.
洪副官
This is
这位
Deputy Hong, from the
是淞沪警备司令部的
Shanghai Garrison Command.
洪副官
If you have any requests,
你们有什么要求
you can talk to him.
可以跟他提
This has nothing to do with him.
这事跟他没什么关系
What sort of rookie bull do we have here,
这是哪儿来的小牛犊
reckless and foolish?
又蠢又凶啊
A local station officer?
警察所的
You're just a local station stray dog.
你一个警察所的黑皮狗
What power are you trying to flex here?
你在这儿逞什么能呢
Young man,
年轻人
I've warned you.
我劝过你
How dare you mess with a place under
洪副官关照过的地方
Deputy Hong's watch?
你们也敢
Xiang Yuansheng!
向远生
Don't move! Stay still!
别动 别动
Put it down!
放下
Don't move!
别动
Xiang Yuansheng!
向远生
Nobody move!
都别动
Get backup!
给我叫人去
I'm not leaving
我今天
until this runt is dealt with!
非得把这小兔崽子弄死
Yes, Sir!
是
Some local station cop.
一个破警察所的
Have you ever used a gun before?
你摸过枪吗
Is this your first time?
这头一回吧
Know where you are?
这是什么地儿
This is...
是 是
this is Shanghai Garrison Command
这是淞沪警备司令部的
territory!
地盘
You think you can just act up here?
你也敢动
Listen up,
我跟你说
if you are to stir up trouble here,
你要敢动这儿
you'd better check
你得问问参谋长
if the Staff Chief agrees!
同不同意
Alright then,
好
I'll check if he agrees.
那我就问问他同不同意
[Hello.]
你好
Connect me to the Shanghai Garrison Command.
接淞沪警备司令部
I need to speak with Staff Chief Tong.
我找佟参谋长
Director An.
安处长
Captain Wei, you are here too?
魏队长也在呢
Has the Staff Chief returned yet?
参谋长还没回来呢
No.
没回来
I'm also waiting for him.
我这不也在等他吗
Hello?
喂
Staff Chief Tong's office.
佟参谋长办公室
The Chief is out at a meeting.
参谋长出去开会了
This is Deputy An Yin speaking.
我是副官处安殷
[It's me, Xiang Yuansheng.]
是我 向远生
Is this Hua Zhen?
是华桢吗
Sorry
抱歉
for the grudge with your men.
把你手下的人给打了
I understand.
我知道了
I'm heading over now.
现在过去
Director An.
安处长
It's Mr. Hua, isn't it?
是华先生吧
Has he
是不是
run into any trouble?
华先生遇到什么麻烦了
Captain Wei,
魏队长对他
still so concerned about him, huh?
还是这么关心啊
By the way,
对了
has your investigation of Hua Zhen
你对华桢的审查
been cleared?
通过了吗
Investigation?
审查
I know
你们侦查队
your men are scrutinizing
最近不是一直
Hua Zhen lately.
在调查华桢吗
It's merely a misunderstanding.
误会误会
My last inquiry
上次跟安处长
about Mr. Hua
询问华先生的事儿
was purely out of personal curiosity.
纯属是我个人的好奇
We've already clarified
华先生跟邓铭远
that tiny bit of mentorship connection
那一点点师生关系
he had with Deng Mingyuan.
我们已经搞清楚了
I see.
这样啊
He is currently
华桢现在
with our
跟我们副官处的人
deputy's team,
在一起
and I'm about to meet him.
我要过去见他
How about
要不
joining me, Captain Wei,
魏队长跟我一起过去
adding some excitement?
凑个热闹
No, no.
不了不了不了
Our investigation team
我们侦查队
is just swamped with work.
实在是事情太多
I really can't spare any time.
我实在是走不开
It's fine,
没关系
Director An.
安处长
How about this:
要不这样
I'll pass on the documents
我替您把资料
to Chief Tong for you.
转交给佟参谋长
You go ahead.
您该忙忙您的
Don't keep your friend waiting.
别让您同学等急了
Thanks for that.
那就多谢了
Don't mention it.
应该的
Really not coming?
真不去了
No.
不去了
Line up!
列队
Director An.
安处长
I won't go in.
我就不进去了
Sort everything out,
你去把事情解决完
then bring Deputy Hong.
然后把洪副官带出来
Go on.
去吧
Yes, Sir!
是
Follow me!
跟我来
Put the guns down!
把枪放下
Captain Jia,
贾队长
what... what brings you here?
您 您怎么来了
Deputy Hong, flexing your authority
洪副官好大的官威
and calling in backup?
还喊上人了
Is the Shanghai Garrison Command
淞沪警备司令部
run by you now?
你说了算
No, no,
不是不是
it's all a misunderstanding.
绝对是误会
Director An is here as well?
安处长也来了
Why?
什么意思
Were you expecting Director An
你还想让安处长
to personally summon you?
亲自来请您
No, no, absolutely not.
不是不是不是
It's all... It's all Mr. Fan's fault...
都 都怨那范老板
Take him away!
带走
Yes, Sir!
是
Mr. Xiang, sorry for the trouble.
向先生 您受惊了
Director An
安处长
sent me to escort you out.
交代我来接您离开
I apologize
不好意思
for the confrontation with your people.
跟你们的人动手了
There were
实在是
urgent matters I needed to handle.
有必须要办的事情
It's we who have inconvenienced you.
是我们给您添麻烦了
About the urgent matter
您说的
you mentioned,
必须要办的事儿
is there anything we can help with?
我能帮上忙吗
No need.
不用帮忙
I can manage it on my own.
我自己都能办好
Everything will be fine.
一定能办好
Don't worry.
放心
It seems the trouble is over then.
看来是不用麻烦了
Alright,
好
I won't disturb you further.
那我就先不打扰了
Director An will be waiting for you outside.
安处长会在外面等您
Mr. Fan,
范老板
back to the matter at hand.
还是这件事儿
Who's looking
是谁在找
for the girl in this photo?
照片上这个女孩儿
About half a month ago,
大概半个多月前
someone called our pawnshop
有人打电话到当铺
to set up this deal.
要做这笔买卖
They sent the photo
照片和酬金
and payment,
都是寄过来的
along with a phone number.
还给了一个电话号码
They instructed me to call that number
让我找到人以后呢
once I found the person.
就打这个号码通知他们
I've never met them
我从头到尾都没见过
in person.
还没见过他们
Don't even know
确实不知道
who they are.
对方的身份哪
So, you gave the address on Wangyun Road
那望云路的地址
to the person
你就是告诉了
who left the phone number?
这个留电话的人
That's right.
对
And where does that number lead?
打过去是什么地方
Fetch the notebook.
去拿本子
Here it is.
找到了
Fuqingli No. 16.
府青里十六号
The Shanghai Garrison Command?
淞沪警备司令部的
I'll go over and say hi.
我过去跟他打个招呼
Thank you, An Yin.
安殷 谢了
Don't mention it.
小事儿
You said, outside the Fourth Station that day,
那天在四所门口
once things settled down,
你说等事情解决了
you'd explain everything to me.
就跟我解释清楚
Can you tell me
现在能告诉我
what exactly
你来上海
brought you to Shanghai?
到底是干什么的吗
Have some fruits.
吃水果
Can we speak privately?
我能跟你单独谈吗
It's fine.
没关系
He's a friend
他是我朋友
and also an officer from the Fourth Station.
也是四所警察
When I first arrived at Shanghai,
我刚来上海的时候
I inquired information from you.
跟你打听过一件事儿
You mean the Meng case?
你说孟家的案子啊
Right.
对
A friend asked me to do him a favor.
我朋友托我来上海
Initially, I just planned
本来打算
a couple of days in Shanghai,
待个两三天就回去
but I came across something.
没想到遇到这件事儿
I didn't return Nanjing
我没回南京啊
because I wanted to
就是想把这个案子
clear up this case.
调查清楚
What friend?
什么朋友啊
A friend from Nanjing.
一个南京的朋友
You wouldn't know him.
你没见过
I asked you once before,
之前我问过你一次
and I need to
现在我还是要
ask again.
再问你一次
Deng Mingyuan from the Navy Dept., a Communist,
海军部的共产党邓铭远
does he have any connection
你查这个案子
to this case you're investigating?
到底跟他有没有关系
This is my own business.
这是我自己的事儿
It has
跟他
nothing to do with him
还有我的家人
or my family.
都没有关系
Investigating cases
查案子
is the duty of policeman.
那是警察该办的事儿
Why are you always
至于你成天
mixing with those low-tier cops?
跟这帮不入流的警察混
Do you have any information on Deng Mingyuan?
那你有邓铭远的消息吗
Where is he being held?
他现在被关在哪儿
You know nothing?
你什么都不知道啊
Neither do I.
我也不知道
I rarely pay attention
我很少关心
to things outside the Deputy Office.
副官处以外的事儿
He's probably under investigation.
估计正在接受调查吧
If there's any result,
要真有结果
it would be communicated internally.
会党内通报的
Let me have a word with the shop owner.
我去跟老板说两句话
Mr. Fan,
范老板
I have a favor to ask.
我有事儿拜托
If anyone inquires
如果有人向你打听
who gave you the address
是谁给了您望云路
for the girl on Wangyun Road,
那个女孩儿的地址
just act as if you don't know.
您就当不知道吧
Sorry for
不好意思
the disruption to your business.
耽误了店铺生意
Here's some compensation.
这是给您的一些补偿
No need.
不必了
How could I possibly take your money?
您的钱我哪敢收啊
Well, I'll accept it.
那我就收下了
What's your relation to the mahjong parlor?
你跟麻将馆什么关系啊
That's irrelevant.
跟麻将馆没有关系
It's just about protecting an innocent family.
只是事关一家无辜的人
I don't want to drag them into this.
我不想连累他们
Shall we
走吧
grab a meal together?
一起吃个饭
There's a new Italian restaurant
警备司令部附近
near the Garrison Command
有家新开的意大利餐厅
that offers good food.
还不错
No, thanks.
不用了
Aren't you
你小子不是
a fan of Italian food?
最爱吃意大利菜吗
You've done enough for me already.
已经很麻烦你了
You realize that, huh?
你还知道啊
Seriously though,
说正经的
does he
他
know you're a military academy student?
知道你是军校的学生吗
He doesn't.
不知道
I heard
听说
you made it into the elite class.
你已经入选精英班了
Getting involved in brawls off-campus.
校外打架滋事
If the academy finds that out,
这要被学校知道
you could face serious disciplinary actions.
是要挨处分的
Not just rejected by the elite class,
到时候别说精英班
but kicked out of the academy altogether.
学校你都回不去了
Did you think about that before you came here?
来之前你想过吗
I did.
想过
But I couldn't worry about that anymore.
但已经顾不上了
Hua Zhen,
华桢
I consider you as my brother,
我拿你当兄弟
and helping you out
你有麻烦我帮你解决
is no big deal for me.
这都是小事儿
But if I ever find out
但如果哪天你让我发现
you have any ties to Deng Mingyuan,
你跟邓铭远有任何瓜葛
then let's not see each other anymore.
以后我们就别见面了
You can go now.
走吧
Director,
处长
is he your friend?
那是您朋友
Yes,
对
my best friend from Army University.
我在陆大最好的朋友
I always admired
以前我最佩服的
his cool head and discipline.
就是他的冷静和自律
Lately, I just can't make sense of him anymore.
现在越来越看不懂他了
How about some food?
吃饭啊
Sure.
好啊
What do you want to eat?
吃什么
Anything.
无所谓
Whatever you usually have
你平常吃什么
is fine with me.
我就吃什么
Then I'll show you a really good place.
那我带你去个好地方
Captain Chen is here.
陈队长来了
How're you doing?
叔叔
Hi.
你好
Captain Chen, welcome.
陈队长来了
Table for two.
两个人
Sure.
好
Sit.
坐
This is the good place you said?
这就是你说的好地方
Give it a try.
尝尝
Haven't eaten at a place like this before?
没在这种地方吃过饭啊
You used to work
你原来是
for the Shanghai Garrison Command?
淞沪警备司令部的
Not exactly.
不是啊
Gentlemen,
两位
here are your noodles.
面来了啊
Enjoy your meal.
二位慢点吃
Have a try.
尝尝
Boss,
老板
I'm leaving the money here.
钱放这里了
Smells pretty good.
闻起来还挺香的
It's even better with vinegar.
加醋更好吃
Vinegar,
醋
boss.
老板
Here, give it to me.
来 给我
I don't like vinegar.
我不吃醋
Take mine.
吃我的
You mentioned the Communist
你们刚刚说的共产党
Deng Mingyuan.
邓铭远
Do you know him?
你认识邓铭远
He was my teacher.
他是我的老师
Why?
怎么了
Nothing. Just asking.
没什么 随便问问
You're not going to eat?
你不吃吗
I'm eating.
吃
Is it delicious?
好吃吗
Not bad.
还不错
Your treat.
给钱吧
Who?
谁啊
You.
你啊
I give all my money to pawnbroker.
我的钱都给当铺老板了
Naughty boy.
臭小子
I'm going.
走了
[OK, welcome next time.]
好 再来啊
Where is the previous gatekeeper?
之前那个门房呢
Well,
这
I don't know,
警官
Officer.
这个我也不清楚
I just began to work here.
我是刚来的
The last gatekeeper...
之前的门房
Who told you to change the gatekeeper?
谁让你们换人的
I registered in
我之前在职业介绍所
in an employment agency.
登了记找工作
The agency asked me to come,
介绍所让我来
so here I am.
这 我就来了
I want the guest register of this building.
这栋楼的房客登记簿
We have it.
这个有这个有
Now!
拿来啊
I'm on it.
好好好
From the previous gatekeeper.
之前的门房留下来的
In the apartment,
出事这间公寓
besides Hua Zhen,
除了这个华桢
there should also live a girl.
明明还住着一个女孩儿
Why didn't you register her?
怎么没登记
Officer,
警官
I'm new here
我这刚来的
and I really don't know
之前的事情
what happened before me.
我是真的不知道啊警官
Sir, someone cleared out the room.
科长 东西都被清空了
Feng Sir,
科长
I've been to Dongguang pawnshop.
我去过东光当铺了
All get out.
都出去
Yes, sir.
是
It's pawnbroker
这个地址
who gave this address
确实是当铺老板
to Nakamura's subordinate,
通知里见手下的
but he said the address
但他说这个地址
had been written on a note
是有人写在纸条上
and slipped under the door
然后从门缝
of the pawnshop.
塞到当铺里的
He didn't see who it was.
他没看见对方是什么人
But there were other cops
但今天除了我们
besides us
还有其他警察
who asked about it today.
也去问过这件事
Who?
谁
Staff of the Fourth Station House,
四所的
one surnamed Chen and the other surnamed Xiang.
一个姓陈一个姓向的
They asked
他们问
who is looking for
是谁在找
the girl in the photo.
照片上的女孩儿
The pawnbroker
当铺老板
gave them
把那边的电话和地址
the phone number and address.
都告诉他们了
No. 16 Fuqingli?
府青里十六号
Yes.
对
Hello?
喂
[Is this]
请问是
[No. 23, Wangyun Road?]
望云路二十三号公寓吗
Yes.
是
Who are you?
你是哪位
I'm the Second Secretary of Office of Aides.
我是侍从室第二处秘书
Who's speaking?
你哪位
Second Secretary of Office of Aides?
侍从室第二秘书
I'm the Chairman Jiang.
我还蒋委员长呢
Hello?
喂
What's up, Liang?
怎么了 梁儿
I wanted to call Hua Zhen
本来想打电话
and asked when he would be back.
问问华桢什么时候回来
But the phone number
结果这个电话号码
seems to be wrong.
好像不对
Secretary.
秘书
Every day I'm here wiping butts.
我天天在这儿擦屁股
constantly cleaning up the mess
我不停在后边
they leave behind.
收拾烂摊子
They're up front,
他们在前面
constantly causing me trouble.
不停给我捅娄子
What do they think I am, a nanny?
当我是奶妈呀
Sir, sir.
科长 科长
Thank you.
谢谢
Good day.
好 慢走
Something went wrong to Zhang.
老张可能出事了
What happened?
什么情况
I went to his house,
我去他家看过
and if he had come back safely,
如果他安全回来过
he would put the flowerpot on the windowsill,
就会按照惯例
as usual.
把花盆放在窗台上
But I found
但是我看了
there was no security signal.
没有安全信号
Anything abnormal
他去医院之前
before he went to the hospital?
打电话有什么不一样吗
No, he was conscious.
没有 他神志很清楚
He said he would go home
他说处理完伤口之后
after treating the wound.
就回家
Junyu,
珺昱
we have to prepare
我们可能要做好
for the worst situation.
最坏的打算
The gatekeeper of Qiushi's apartment
秋实住的公寓那个门房
knew her and Xiang Yuansheng.
认识她和向远生
I'm afraid of troubles after that,
我怕之后有什么麻烦
so I changed the gatekeeper.
已经把门房换掉
Zhang gave this to Xiang Yuansheng
这是老张去医院之前
before he went to the hospital.
交给向远生的
He wanted to leave us clues.
他是要给我们留下线索
The murderer used this dagger
凶手就是用这把匕首
to stab his leg.
插在他腿上
I had it checked.
我查过了
It's FS dagger,
这是防身格斗匕首
a popular
目前的
patrol dagger.
英美明星巡捕匕首
The murderer
凶手肯定不是
must have gotten it
通过正常途径
through a private source.
拿到匕首的
I'll check with the Municipal Council.
我从工部局查一下
The lost records of this dagger
应该很快能查到
should be found soon.
匕首的丢失记录
I left Zhang in the apartment
是我把老张留在公寓
to protect Qiushi.
负责保护秋实的
I worked with him for five years.
我们一起工作五年
He helped me through numerous difficulties.
他帮我渡过了无数难关
But I couldn't protect him.
但我没能保护好他
How did he die?
怎么死了
We used too much torture.
我们用刑太重了点儿
Never excuse.
行了行了行了
Did he have anything
他身上
with him?
有什么随身的东西吗
It's all there.
都在那儿
This
这个
was tied to his wound.
是绑在他伤口上的
Tied on the wound?
绑在伤口上
Correct.
对
Probably,
你说
it belongs to the cop
会不会是送他
who took him to the hospital?
去医院的那个警察的
Are you kidding me?
开什么玩笑
Impossible.
不可能
Look at this belt.
看看这条皮带
This belt buckle alone
光这个皮带头
is worth six months' pay
就可以顶他们警察
of a cop.
半年的薪水
[Shunchang.]
顺昌
Hurry and organize personnel
赶紧的 组织人手
to help me look into
帮我查一下
all the high-end clothing stores
所有印着顺昌
and leather shops
这两个字的
that bear the name Shunchang.
高级服装店和皮具店
All over Shanghai?
整个上海吗
No,
不
check Nanjing
先查
first.
南京
You're back, Captain Chen.
陈队长回来了
Are you cooking?
做饭呢
Yeah, I'm off duty.
下班了
This Chinese medicine has such a strong odor.
每次这个中药味特别大
[One more, please.]
老板再带上我一个
[Off duty, Captain Chen?]
陈队长下班了
[Back home, bro?]
回来了哥
[You're back, Captain Chen.]
陈队长回来了
Leek, I know you like it.
韭菜 你喜欢的呀
It smells so good.
老香了
I'll keep one for you.
等下捞出来一碗
Ok.
好好好
I'll call you later.
等下叫你
Thank you.
谢谢
Xiaomei,
小妹啊
boil a few more.
你等一下多煮几碗啊
[Captain Chen,]
陈队长
[come over.]
过来 过来
[Come.]
来 过来
[Back, Captain Chen?]
陈队长回来了
[You play cards every day.]
天天玩牌
[Don't you care about anything at home.]
家里什么你都不管
[It's okay, let him play.]
没事就打打牌吧
[It's your fault.]
就是你 就是你
[You set a bad example.]
天天带他玩牌
[Don't get addicted. Go!]
痴多少迷 走了
Come on in.
进嘛
You can't live in the apartment anymore.
公寓肯定是不能住了
You can live with me.
最近你先住我这儿吧
Just make do with it.
将就将就
There are two
反正这两个房子
rooms of similar size.
房型也差不多
I'll get you a glass of water.
我给你倒杯水
[Captain Chen,]
陈队长
[dumpling is ready, come and eat.]
饺子好了 快点来吃呀
I'm coming.
来了
Drink some water.
你先喝口水
Sister.
阿姐
Are two pans enough?
两份够吗
Come again if not.
不够再来了哦
It is enough.
可以了
Please feel free to ask.
不要客气哦
Thank you.
谢谢你啊
Eat dumplings.
来 吃饺子
Is that book again?
又是那本书啊
You do like the book, right?
你很喜欢这本书吗
You carry the book with you.
这时候还带着
What does this mean?
这是什么意思
Its literal translation is
直接翻译过来就是
Moment for Human to Make Choice.
人类的选择时刻
The person who gave me this book said
送这本书给我的人说
it also can be translated into
也可以翻译成
Decisive Moments in History.
人类的群星闪耀时
Have a look?
看看吗
And this?
这个呢
The greatest fortune in life
人生最大的幸运
is to discover one's destination
莫过于在年富力强时
when still in his prime.
发现了自己的人生使命
-You've finished it all? -I did.
你都看完了
What is it talking about?
说的什么呀
Moments.
时刻
Some decisive moments
一些改变了人类历史的
that change human history,
决定性时刻
are also decisive moments of lifetime.
也是人生的决定性时刻
Let me read for you.
给你读一段
[Such dramatic]
这种充满戏剧性
[and fateful moments]
和命运攸关的时刻
[are rare]
在个人的一生中
[in an individual's life]
和在历史的进程中
[and in the course of history.]
都十分难得
[And such moments]
这种时刻
[often occur only on a single day,]
往往只发生在某一天
[at a single hour,]
某一小时
[and even]
甚至常常
[at a single minute.]
只发生在某一分钟
[But their decisive impact]
但它们的决定性影响
[extends beyond time.]
却超越时间
[I want to review such decisive]
我想在本书中
[and shining moments]
从极其不同的时代
[in different eras]
和地区
[and regions]
回顾这样一些
[in this book.]
群星闪耀的时刻
[I call them so]
我之所以如此称呼它们
[because they are]
是因为它们
[like stars,]
宛如星辰一般
[radiating their light forever]
永远散射着光辉
[and illuminating]
普照着
[the vanishing darkness,]
终将消失的黑夜
As the author
这是作者
wrote the words in the preface.
在序言里写的一段话
Anyone home?
在家吗
I'm coming.
来了
Captain Chen,
陈队长
I just heard from someone in the alley that
我刚刚听弄堂口的人说
you got a roommate.
您家有人搬进来
I have to register it
这按规矩
according to the regulations.
我得登记一下
You know
你也知道
how strict the management is now.
现在管人管得严
A friend of mine
我有个朋友
will stay here for a few days.
来我家住几天
Can you show me
那能把他的证件
his ID certificate?
给我看看吗
My peer.
同行啊
Captain Chen,
陈队长
I'll go to the Household Registration Section
那我回总局户籍科
to cross check it.
核实下底档
I'm leaving.
就不打扰你们了
He is a new recruit
他是四所
of the Fourth Station this year.
今年新招的警员
His identification
户籍科已经查过了
has been confirmed to be fine.
证件没问题
By whom?
谁查的
Me.
我
Alright then.
那我就放心了
See you.
那我先走了啊
Bye.
慢走啊
The dumplings are getting cold. Let's eat
饺子凉了 吃饭吧
When did you know
你从什么时候开始知道
I use a fake ID?
我用的是假证件
From the very beginning.
一开始
Since I came to the Fourth Station?
从我来四所报到的时候
Almost.
差不多吧
Back at Wenhua Hotel,
文华饭店遇害的
in addition to Li Qiushi's parents,
除了黎秋实的父母
there was
还有一名
a 20-year-old man got killed.
二十多岁的男性
The ID is his.
你手上的证件是他的
He was Xiang Yuansheng.
他才是向远生
The real Xiang Yuansheng
真正的向远生
is a missing person.
是失踪人口
He has been missing for over three years.
失踪年限已经超过三年
No immediate family in Shanghai,
在上海没有直系亲属
and his landlord
租房的房东
is his only
是他唯一的
stakeholder.
利益相关人士
The court has passed
法院已经通过
the landlord's application
房东的申请
and declared the man dead.
宣告这个人死亡了
But his household registration file
但他的户籍底档
has not been cancelled yet.
还没有销户
How do you know this?
你怎么知道这些
On the way out of the pawnshop,
从当铺出来的时候
you asked me if I knew Deng Mingyuan.
你问我认不认识邓铭远
And you?
你呢
You know him?
认识他吗
No.
不认识
You said this certificate
你说过
was entrusted to you by a friend.
这张证件是受朋友所托
Whoever gave it to you,
不管是谁给你的
I think he trusted you enough
我想他都非常地信任你
to give it to you.
才会把这个交给你
I knew a person
我曾经也遇到过
who believed in me very much,
一个非常信任我的人
and he said I could be a good cop.
他说我能做一名好警察
I think
我想他在
when he said that,
说这句话的时候
it was a decisive moment for me.
也是我的决定性时刻
I just don't know
只是不知道今后
if I'll ever see him again.
还有没有机会见到他
Come in.
进
Warden Liu.
刘典狱长
Staff Chief Tong.
佟参谋长
When did you arrive at Shanghai?
什么时候到的上海
Just arrived this afternoon.
下午刚到
The Ministry of Military Affairs has decided
军政部决定
to extradite Deng Mingyuan to Nanjing,
将邓铭远押解回南京
and transfer him to the Central Military Prison.
移交至中央军人监狱
Mr. He ordered me
何部长命我来
to handle the relevant procedure in person.
亲自来办理相关手续
Here is the handover paperwork.
这个 移交文书
I got a call from Mr. He.
我接到何部长电话了
Is there a verdict on Deng?
邓的判决有结果了
Not yet,
目前还没有
but Navy Dept. has confirmed that
但是海军部已经查实
he is linked with a leak case
他和三年前的
three years ago.
一桩泄密案有关
His death penalty
死刑
is only a matter of time.
只是时间早晚的问题
Go,
去
and handle procedures for the Warden.
跟着看守长办手续
Yes, sir.
是
This is handover paperwork.
这是交接文书
He's even in the mood to paint.
他还有心情画画
What kind of boat is it?
画的什么船
Take him to verification,
带他去验身
and make an inventory of his items.
清点下物品
All his carry-on items are here.
他就这点东西
Have a check.
点一下吧
This way.
这边
Comrade 037,
零三七同志
I'm ordered
我奉
by the Nanjing underground party
南京地下党组织命令
to rescue you now.
来救你
Step on it.
站上去
We'll take action
移交南京之前
before you're handed over to Nanjing.
我们会动手
The handcuff key will be delivered to you.
手铐钥匙会送到你手里
The first yard time in tomorrow afternoon.
明天午后第一次放风
You go near the southeast sentry post,
东南角岗亭附近
which is
那里是
a blind spot of the watchtower.
瞭望塔的视线死角
A rope will be thrown down there,
有人会扔下来一根绳子
and when the guards are distracted,
在狱警被吸引走之后
you must get rid of
你只要解决掉
the man in the booth,
岗亭里那个人
and get over the wall.
就能翻出围墙
Our comrade
我们的同志
will meet you outside.
就在外面接应你
Teach him a lesson.
给我好好解决这个人
I want him not to go against me
我要让他有十个胆
forever.
也不敢跟我对着干
Keep him alive or not?
留活口吗